<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<property xmlns="https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
   xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
   xsi:schemaLocation="https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/
   https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/properties_files.xsd">
   <uid>p79</uid>
   <labels>
      <platformIndependent>staffNotes</platformIndependent>
      <dc>none</dc>
   </labels>
   <uwRequired>
      <uwStandalone>no</uwStandalone>
      <uwObject>no</uwObject>
      <uwItem>no</uwItem>
   </uwRequired>
   <cdm>
      <label>Staff Notes</label>
      <cdmDatatype>text</cdmDatatype>
      <cdmLarge>no</cdmLarge>
      <searchable>no</searchable>
      <hidden>yes</hidden>
      <cdmRequired>no</cdmRequired>
      <cdmControlledVocab>no</cdmControlledVocab>
   </cdm>
   <dspace>
      <dspaceProperty/>
   </dspace>
   <descriptions>
      <definition>
         <para>Notes for staff only, notes of an administrative nature.</para>
      </definition>
      <instructions co="no">
         <para>Input your staff notes however you wish.</para>
      </instructions>
      <instructions co="object">
         <para>Input your staff notes however you wish.</para>
      </instructions>
      <instructions co="item">
         <para>Input your staff notes however you wish.</para>
      </instructions>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="text">
         <para>Staff Notes values are hidden in the public CONTENTdm interface.</para>
         <para>These values will be used by University of Washington Libraries (UWL) cataloging staff to assign controlled values for the following fields for textual resources.</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;For books, catalogers may supply values for:</para>
         <para>Subjects (LCSH)</para>
         <para>Genre/Form (LCGFT)</para>
         <para>Related OCLC Record</para>
         <para>Printer Location</para>
         <para>Publisher Location</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;For ephemera, catalogers may supply values for:</para>
         <para>Subjects (LCSH)</para>
         <para>Genre/Form (LCGFT)</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;To facilitate cataloging of books:</para>
         <para>Briefly summarize the genre, subject, and intended use.</para>
         <para>Descriptions of novels should briefly summarize the arc of the story.</para>
         <para>For religious texts, such as prayer books and bibles, note for which Jewish holiday and/or ritual they are used.</para>
         <para>Note if the work is a translation, and the author and language of the original text.</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;To facilitate cataloging of ephemera:</para>
         <para>Record any relevant information characterizing the resource which isn’t included in values for any other metadata field.</para>
         <para>Translate non-English text or terminology to aid cataloging staff in metadata creation.</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;Required for all textual-resource compound objects which will require subject or genre/form analysis from UWL cataloging staff.</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="song">
         <para>Staff Notes values are hidden in the public CONTENTdm interface.</para>
         <para>These values will be used by University of Washington Libraries (UWL) cataloging staff to assign controlled values for the following fields for ballad recordings:</para>
         <para>Genre/Form (LCGFT)</para>
         <para>Performer Birthplace</para>
         <para>Recording Location</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;Staff notes should not be necessary for UWL catalogers entering structured values for ballad recordings.</para>
         <para>Other staff notes may be entered as needed.</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="Oral_histories">
         <para>Staff Notes values are hidden in the public CONTENTdm interface.</para>
         <para>These values will be used by University of Washington Libraries (UWL) cataloging staff to assign controlled values for the following fields for oral histories:</para>
         <para>Subjects (LCSH)</para>
         <para>Genre/Form (LCGFT)</para>
         <para>Geographic Coverage</para>
         <para>Interviewee Birthplace</para>
         <para>Recording Location</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;Add any available relevant information which is not given in Index, Notes, or other property values, which will assist UWL catalogers assigning values for Subjects (LCSH) and Geographic Coverage.</para>
         <para>Catalogers will the use unstructured values provided for Interviewee Birthplace and Recording Location to create structured values for these fields, so Staff Notes will not be required for them.</para>
      </customization>
   </descriptions>
   <examples>
      <example co="no">
         <para>Al, could you look at this one?</para>
         <para>Still need to research the difference between the saws pictured.</para>
      </example>
      <example co="object">
         <para>Al, could you look at this one?</para>
         <para>Still need to research the difference between the saws pictured.</para>
      </example>
      <example co="item">
         <para>Al, could you look at this one?</para>
         <para>Still need to research the difference between the saws pictured.</para>
      </example>
      <customization co="object" dd="greekdancing">
         <para>Note 2023-05-01: Double check values for Instruments Depicted.</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="item" dd="greekdancing">
         <para>Note 2023-05-01: Found an incorrect Digital Collection value; please recheck these values.</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="text">
         <para>For books:</para>
         <para>A Ladino translation of the French novel "Paul et Virginie" by Bernardin de Saint-Pierre (1737-1814). This short love story, set in the 18th century on a French island, tells of a man a woman separated by distance and circumstance, never to be united before their untimely deaths.</para>
         <para>This is a parallel Hebrew-Ladino translation of the Book of Ruth with corresponding commentary in Ladino. The Book of Ruth is part of the Old Testament found in the section known as Ketuvim (Writings). It is traditionally read on the Jewish holiday of Shavuot (Feast of Weeks).</para>
         <para>&lt;br/&gt;For ephemera:</para>
         <para>This is a wedding certificate decorated with a floral pattern behind a picture of a menorah (Jewish candelabra) and an open book with the words “Siman Tov u-Mazal Tov,” a Hebrew phrase often used to congratulate a couple on their wedding. </para>
         <para>The Ladino text in this cigarette advertisement reads “A high-quality product.”</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="song">
         <para>N/A</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="Oral_histories">
         <para>Interviewee discusses time spent in Los Angeles in great detail.</para>
         <para>Interviewee discusses experiences of religious discrimination in great detail.</para>
      </customization>
      <customization co="no" dd="p16786coll3">
         <para>Rosh ha-Shanah postcard featuring a pink plush heart with the words “טובה לשנה” “La-Shanah Tovah” [A Happy New Year] embroidered in the center with gold glitter. Postcard features a glitter design of a Star of David below two doves. In the center of the star is the image of a woman’s hand shaking a man’s hand. Printed in English, “With My Good Wishes And Hearty Greetings, A Happy New Year” and “Le-Shanah Tova Tikhtevu” [May you be inscribed for a Happy New Year] printed in Hebrew characters.</para>
      </customization>
   </examples>
   <additionalInfo>
      <admin co="all">
         <para>Customarily this field is searchable in CONTENTdm while the collection is being developed; when the collection is done, the field should not be searchable.</para>
      </admin>
   </additionalInfo>
   <marc>
      <dcgMarcMapping/>
      <marcNotes>
         <para/>
      </marcNotes>
   </marc>
   <xsd>
      <typeInfo level="standalone object item">
         <typeAttribute>xs:string</typeAttribute>
      </typeInfo>
   </xsd>
   <rdf> </rdf>
   <history>
      <dateCreated>
         <range>
            <start>2000-01-01</start>
            <end>2017-01-12</end>
         </range>
      </dateCreated>
      <created4Coll>Special Collections Photograph Collections</created4Coll>
      <justification>Staff needed a way to communicate about administering the resource inside CONTENTdm, so we created this property.</justification>
      <changeLog>
         <change date="2017-10-23">changed //cdm/required to //cdm/cdmRequired and //cdm/uwRequired to assist in halting use of the cdm "required" feature while, at the same time, indicating that UW-cdm collections must use, or not use, a given property; also changed @xsi:schemaLocation.</change>
         <change date="2018-03-23">Added some cdm compound object information</change>
         <change date="2018-03-27">Added item info</change>
         <change date="2021-10-27">Add custom instructions and examples for SSDC; still in progress</change>
      </changeLog>
   </history>
</property>
