<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<property xmlns="https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/
    https://uwlib-mig.github.io/schemasProject/xsd/properties_files.xsd">
    <uid>p117</uid>
    <labels>
        <platformIndependent>titleALALCR</platformIndependent>
        <dc>alternative</dc>
    </labels>
    <uwRequired>
        <uwStandalone>no</uwStandalone>
        <uwObject>no</uwObject>
        <uwItem>no</uwItem>
    </uwRequired>
    <cdm>
        <label>Title (ALA-LC Romanization)</label>
        <cdmDatatype>text</cdmDatatype>
        <cdmLarge>no</cdmLarge>
        <searchable>yes</searchable>
        <hidden>no</hidden>
        <cdmRequired>no</cdmRequired>
        <cdmControlledVocab>no</cdmControlledVocab>
    </cdm>
    <!-- omit dspace -->
    <dspace>
        <dspaceProperty/>
    </dspace>
    <descriptions>
        <definition>
            <para>A non-Latin script title which has been Romanized according to the ALA-LC Romanization Tables.</para>
        </definition>
        <instructions co="all">
            <para>Provide a non-Latin script title which has been Romanized according to the ALA-LC Romanization Tables.</para>
        </instructions>
        <customization co="object" dd="p16786coll3" genre_form="text">
            <para>Search for Romanized title in &lt;a href="http://catdir.loc.gov/catdir/toc/becites/ladino/63062107a.html"&gt;LOC Ladino catalog.&lt;/a&gt;</para>
            <para>If a potential match is found, confirm that it is the correct title. It may be helpful to review information included in the web display such as the publisher, printer, and publisher/printer locations.</para>
            <para>Copy the Romanized title just as it appears in the LOC record, usually following the period after the author name.</para>
            <para>When copying from LOC, retain this version: do not edit to match the Title value for the resource.</para>
            <para>If no record exists, Romanize according to the ALA-LC &lt;a href="https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/romanization/ladino.pdf"&gt;Ladino romanization table.&lt;/a&gt;</para>
            <para>When Romanizing a title, only include the portion transcribed in the Title field.</para>
            <para>Note: Titles in the Library of Congress’ online Ladino catalog do not always conform to current ALA-LC romanization standards. Copy catalog those entries as-is into this field. If the title does not exist in the online catalog, romanize according to the ALA-LC standard.</para>
            <para>Use space, colon, space (" : ") to indicate a break between title and subtitle, even if no colon appears on the title page.</para>
            <para>Subtitles should be lowercase, including the first word, except for proper nouns.</para>
            <para>Following the title and colon, record a minimum of five words of the subtitle, followed by an ellipsis (“…”) if not recording the complete subtitle.</para>
            <para>Consult &lt;a href="https://www.loc.gov/cds/desktop/documents/Hebraica_cataloging.pdf"&gt;Hebraica Cataloging&lt;/a&gt; (pgs. 20-23) for instructions related to rashe tevot (Hebrew abbreviations).</para>
            <para>Words of Hebrew-Aramaic origin should be romanized according to the &lt;a href="https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/romanization/hebrew.pdf"&gt;ALA-LC Hebrew and Yiddish Romanization Table&lt;/a&gt;.</para>
            <para>In cases where resources are printed in romanized Ladino, leave this field blank.</para>
            <para>Required for all compound objects.</para>
        </customization>
    </descriptions>
    <examples>
        <example co="object">
            <para>Pavlo y Virzhinyah : romanso</para>
        </example>
        <example co="no">
            <para>Pavlo y Virzhinyah : romanso</para>
        </example>
    </examples>
    <!-- Omit:
        additionalInfo
        marc -->
    <!-- BMR TO DO - XSD -->
    <!-- Omit:
        rdf
        cdmRdf -->
    <additionalInfo/>
    <marc>
        <dcgMarcMapping/>
    </marc>
    <xsd/>
    <rdf/>
    <history>
        <dateCreated>
            <single>2021-03-19</single>
        </dateCreated>
        <created4Coll>Sephardic Studies Digital Collection - p16786coll3</created4Coll>
        <justification>SSDC requires Romanized title values in multiple flavors including ALA-LC.</justification>
        <changeLog>
            <change/>
        </changeLog>
    </history>
</property>
